kaki narase sonzai wo
rock away your existence
koko ni iru to
shouting that you are here
arata na tabi ga ima hajimaru
a new journey begins now
kawari yuku kisetsu no naka wo ikinuku tabi ni bokura
as we survived through the changing seasons
chie to tsuyosa wo te ni ireta kedo JUST LOOKS LIKE SURVIVAL GAME
we gained knowledge and strength (just looks like a survival game)
nagareteku jikan no naka ni
but the forgotten memories
okizari ni shita omoi wo
of the feelings abandoned within the flows of time
wasureta koto sura wasurete ita
have also been lost
kuzure kaketa toki kodoku wo shitte
when sinking down we learned loneliness
deaeta bokura hitori ja nai
but now we've met each other we are no longer alone
sarake dase kanjou wo banjou no omoi wo
unveil your feelings those high emotions
namidame ga unmei wo kaete yuku
those tears will change your fate
yami ni uchi narase kodou wo
pound your heartbeat against the darkness
kitto aeru yo onaji itami no hata no moto de
we're sure to meet under the same flag of pain
Say, Grandma Tsunade,
am I really so...?
Come to think of it,
I've felt dull recently
and I make more mistakes
with Jutsu than before.
And even worse...
I can't eat more than five of
the large-size ramen noodles at Ichiraku.
Might I perhaps have
some terrible illness?!
Come on, tell me.
I'm prepared to hear the worst!
You are in good health.
Hey! That's Bushy Brow's
medical record, isn't it?
Recently he's been avoiding
his regular checkups.
Bring him in, will you?
Huh? But what about me?
You are stupid. That's all!
Be on your way!
— Put your clothes back on, you idiot!
— Yes!
Unbelievable!
How was it?
I'm fit as a fiddle!
I could tell that just by looking at you.
What's that all about?
He doesn't seem to be
in a very good mood, does he?
Oh, by the way,
have you seen Bushy Brow?
No, but I know where he is.
These days,
you can always find him here.
2,954, 2,955,
2,956, 2,957, 2,958...
That's just amazing.
Even after having surgery
for the kind of injury
that could prevent him
from continuing on as a Ninja...
— Bushy Brow!
— Lee!
Bushy Brow!
Lee.
It's nothing.
Grandma Tsunade told me
to bring you in for your regular checkup.
It slipped my mind. I've been
feeling fine lately, so I just...
You don't look like it though.
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
Rest for a while.
You are forbidden from engaging in
any missions or training.
There is cumulative damage
to your Chakra Network.
You were once injured so badly
that you had to give up
on being a Ninja for a while.
It's my self-rule.
Your self-rule?
Yes! To never forget
my original intentions!
As long as I keep on trying,
I will be able to continue on as a Ninja!
All right.
I will remove you
from active duty for a while,
but you may continue training.
Just don't overdo it.
Yes!
In particular,
I prohibit you to use Hidden Lotus!
— Got that?
— Yes.
Oh! Hey, Bushy Brow, how did it go?
What's wrong? Hey!
The results were bad.
Judging from the way he looked,
I'd say considerably.
By "considerably"
do you mean that "considerably"?
Yes. Considerable, to be sure.
Considerable?!
What are you so down about?! Lee!
Guy-sensei!
I heard the results of the exam.
You have permission to train, don't you?
Yes, but the Hidden Lotus...
That day, you were crying right there.
Your surgery will be a success
because you have worked hard
all the way through.
You have the power to bring
your own future in the heavens.
And in the one in a thousand...
No, one in a million chance
that something goes wrong...
I'm going to die with you!
Ever since the time I met you,
my Way of Ninja has been
bringing you up to be a fine Ninja.
I promise you!
You believed me then and had the surgery.
And it was successful.
You must have faith in me
one more time!
If you can no longer use the Hidden Lotus,
then strive to attain an even
greater technique through your efforts!
There are no limits
in the face of your efforts.
Sensei!
You are a genius at effort!
Yes, sir!
I'll give you some training
for the first time in quite a spell!
First, dash to the Academy practice hall!
Please instruct me!
If you don't get there in ten seconds,
it's 500 push-ups!
Right!
The Third Super Beast
The Greatest Rival
It was rash of us to think we could
make it in ten seconds, after all.
Just as well!
Five hundred.
It's been a long time
since I smelled this scent.
Who is he?
That's Yagura.
He's been here for a week.
An acquaintance asked me to determine
whether he has aptitude as a Ninja.
His name is Yagura, you say?
He's pretty good, isn't he?
Yes, he has the instincts for it.
He absorbs the things I teach him
like sand absorbs water.
You're Rock Lee, aren't you?
Yes.
I hear that you have superb techniques.
Sensei has told me about you.
No, nothing that great.
Don't be bashful, you.
— Guy-sensei?
— Yes?
I would like to receive some instruction
from my senior.
— Fine, then. Begin!
— Huh?!
Guy-sensei!
You came to train anyway.
First, lend a bit of aid
to your junior partner and warm up.
I see.
He's a spring chick who has just arrived,
so try not to let him get hurt.
Right.
What's Bushy Brow doing in
the Academy practice hall of all places?
I thought
his condition was considerably bad!
Yes, considerably! Considerably!
I'm inexperienced,
but please instruct me.
Oh, please bear with me, too.
Now, Lee and Yagura, I want you both
to give it all you've got,
but to also observe
the greatest courtesy.
That is friendship!
That is youth. Get ready. Fight!
— He's fast!
— Let's have you show me...
the depth of the Taijutsu
that Might Guy drilled into you!
What power!
Every single blow is heavy!
I haven't the strength to absorb them!
Leaf Hurricane!
Closing off the escape path above
and strike from a low position.
However...
The Leaf Hurricane was defeated!
Stop! Hold it right there!
Lee! Are you all right?
Pull yourself together, Bushy Brow!
What was that that just happened?
The Cross Method.
Meeting the opponent's kick
and pinning his foot between
the knee and elbow simultaneously,
a "bone-crushing, daring technique."
Where on earth
did you learn that, Yagura?
I didn't intend to do that.
My body just moved
like that involuntarily.
Sorry, Lee. Are you all right?
If Lee hadn't been wearing his weights,
his ankle would have been crushed.
It was a splendid move. Well, then,
let's continue with the practice.
Let's stop here for today.
I'll take you to the hospital
to have them look at it.
No, I'm completely fine, I tell you.
We knew from the health checkup
that Bushy Brow's injuries were
considerable to begin with, didn't we?
Considerable!
What was considerable?
I'm telling you,
just considerable, right?!
— Probably considerable...
— Considerable, I tell you!
Even with the weights on, that speed...
What was considerable?!
Fortunately, there's nothing wrong
with the bone.
I see.
Um... When can I begin training again?
What are you saying?!
You're going to need complete rest
for a while.
It's amazing that your Achilles tendon
remained uninjured, you know.
You said considerable, so...
I misunderstood it to mean
that he was in a considerable condition.
But...
he came out of the examination room
looking very down,
so I just assumed...
To be sure, he seems dispirited.
He was beaten by a trainee
who isn't even enrolled in the Academy.
A trainee? Lee?
Yes, a kid who has been studying Taijutsu
for only one week.
In any case,
he was incredibly skilled, that...
What's it called...?
— The Cross Method!
— Yes, that!
He's a genius to deploy that
at that instant!
I hope Lee isn't feeling down, though.
If he were the kind of guy to get
downhearted about a thing like that,
Lee would have quit being
a Shinobi a long time ago.
When Lee was in the Academy,
he was told that he had neither
the talent for Ninjutsu,
nor any talent for Genjutsu.
Had it been me,
I would have given up long ago.
But Lee got to where he is now
purely through effort and persistence.
If he can just heal his injuries,
he'll soon outstrip anyone
with natural talent alone.
— That's true.
— Damn right!
But...
I've heard that if you train too hard,
you can wreck your body
and become decrepit...
Don't say such a thing!
You're talking about Bushy Brow!
I'm only kidding.
Just a slip of the tongue.
— Don't even say that in jest!
— Decrepit?
I know, I know.
But, actually, we are grateful to Lee.
Huh? Grateful?
Yes, grateful.
Okay, today I'm going to teach you
about self-rule.
— Self...
— Rule, you say?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Please teach me! Me! Me!
All right, ready?
To all things there are principles,
and to efficiently make use of things
in daily life, human beings have rules.
Okay, today I have something good
to give you all.
— Something...
— Good?
This!
These tights are the type
that I habitually use!
They have outstanding ventilation
and moisture-wicking properties!
Developed for ultimate ease of movement,
it's the complete super-athletic wear!
If you wear them when you're training,
you'll feel the difference immediately!
You won't be able to do without them!
Next thing you know,
you'll be wearing them all the time!
Yes, yes, yes!
Please, by all means, give me a pair!
Oh, I got a pair of those myself.
They look cool, don't they?
Oh, is that so?
If it weren't for Lee...
This is youth!
This is guts!
This is Harutaro Minami,
spring chicken of the South!
— You got that all wrong!
I'm really glad that we've had Lee around.
Yeah, me too.
I'm sure a C-rank mission would
feel insufficient for you,
but there's nobody left to ask.
Leave it to me.
Oh, by the way, there's someone
I'd like to take with me...
Yagura!
When my foot heals,
let's train together aga...
I feel no need to take lessons from you.
Even ruling out the fact
that you were wearing weights,
there seems
to be nothing worth stealing from you.
Stealing?
After all, skills acquired
purely through effort
make you nothing
but a pale imitation of Guy-sensei.
What did you say?!
As proof of that,
even Sensei has given up on you.
That can't be!
Guy-sensei promised me...
that his own Way of Ninja was
to turn me into a splendid Ninja, too!
Well, then, I wonder why he's gone
so far as to ask me
to come on a mission with him
for practical training.
Not you, but me.
You?
Too bad. There's no way
effort can win out over talent.
Wait!
Did Sensei really asked you to...?
No, it... can't be true.
Tsunade-sama!
What is it?
Yagura has been injured
and is under protection.
What? Guy was with him.
What on earth happened?
No! Yagura is said to have been attacked
before reaching Hidden Leaf Village.
Then the trainee Yagura
that accompanied Guy is...
A total imposter.
Damn it, one nuisance after another...!
So, these three are the ones
that can be mobilized?
What shall we do?
Fine! Have Neji, Tenten and Naruto...
these three go after Guy
and the phony Yagura!
— Right!
— Wait!
Have Sakura keep an eye on Lee.
If he learns about this,
he's apt to dash out,
even in the shape he's in.
Right!
Are you sure that Intense Brow Sensei
went this way?
Without a doubt!
His destination was
the Land of Mountain Streams.
He must have gone through this forest.
There's another way to go,
cutting through the mountains,
but it's too dangerous.
Yagura, are you with me?
Yes, Guy-sensei!
Don't slow down!
Take each step after first taking
the measure of the mountain terrain!
Right!
Lee could run through here blindfolded.
What's wrong? Yagura?
Oh, no!
Yagura! Where are you?! Yagura!
Yagura!
He may be a genius,
but he's still a trainee.
I wonder if I expected
too much from him.
Yagura!
What? Were you in such a place?
Wooden Training Dummies
for kung fu training.
Oh, my... It takes me back to my youth.
I trained with a burning spirit on
the same kinds of Wooden Dummies.
It makes my body start
to move uncontrollably.
But why are there Wooden Dummies
in such a place?
Who in the world...?
And for what purpose?
They move well for dummies.
But, after all, they just look
like automated dolls.
They only have one pattern of movement,
and no matter
how many of them there are,
their reach only extends
for a diameter of 3.5 meters,
so they cannot attack.
What? Mister, you can move?!
What the heck?!
Hey? Can't you see anything yet? Neji!
Even using the Byakugan,
I can't find a single footprint.
They can't have gotten that far away,
can they?
They wouldn't have used excessively
dangerous mountain paths either.
However they seem to be able to move,
they're just stick figures crawling
over the surface of the ground.
Mister, you can jump, too?!
Not just yet!
What a...
pleasant, high-energy training place!
6,985, 6,986, 6,987, 6,988,
6,989, 6,990, 6,991...
There is no limit to training.
Even if I cannot use my legs,
my upper half is still in good shape.
Guy-sensei thinks...
my training is inadequate.
That's why he compared me to Yagura,
to show me that I wasn't doing enough.
7,000!
I have faith in Guy-sensei!
They're moderately powerful, but...
their movements are monotonous.
Or so I thought!
Shall I say I am outnumbered?
There seems to be no limit to them!
What is this sound?
What?!
hoshikuzu suchasucha sucha odoru
on a checkerboard night
ichimatsu no yoru ni
when the stardust's are rapidly dancing
aa mada kaeri takunai to kuchi ni wa dasenai naa
I just can't come out and say, "ah, I don't want to go home yet"
omowa seburi terii
suggestively
aisubeki kao ni tsuba wo misutaa kuriketto
spat at that beloved face, mister cricket
asekusai suteeji no ue de hikaru toronboon no
the trombone gradually going off-key
picchi ga dandan hazureteitteiru no mo kininaru kedo
while on the sweaty center stage does bug me
sonna koto yori kono nai mune no moyamoya wa sakki
but more importantly, the fuzziness I feel in my undeveloped chest,
nonda koora no sei kashira nee
I wonder If it's from that coke I just drank?
I thought I knew,
but you do have incredible power, after all.
To think you have such
an amazing kick.
Looks like I have to put out
everything in myself.
Then I would put everything
I've got into this too.
Fine! Why don't you come at me
with intent to beat me?!
Please forgive me Guy-sensei.
But to me, this is the moment...
— to follow through with my own Ninja Way!
Next time:
"Clash of Tears! Hot-Blooded Master-Desciple Battle."